Printed Maps Printed.Maps
American Philosophical Society
- North America
  - United States Of America
    - Middle Atlantic States
      - [A map of part of Pennsylvania, Delaware & Maryland intended to shew, at one view, the several places proposed for opening a communication between the waters of the Delaware & Chesopeak Bays. 1771]., 755; Scale: 2.5 cm. = 7¾ mi.; Size of plate: 31.2 x 44.6 cm.; J. Smither.
        In: American Philosophical Society. Transactions, vol. 1, following p. 292.
        Wheat: 300
      - A general map of the Middle British colonies, in America. Containing Virginia, Maryland, the Delaware Counties, Pennsylvania, and New Jersey. With the addition of New York, and of the greatest part of New England, as also of the bordering parts of the Province of Quebec. Improved from several surveys made after the late war, and corrected from Governor Pownall's late map 1776. [Title on top of sheet]: The seat of war in the middle British colonies, containing Virginia, Maryland, the Delaware Counties, &c. London: R. Sayer and J. Bennett: 1776 [15 October 1776]., 756; Scale: 69½ British statute mi. = 1 degree.; Size: 48.8 x 66.5 cm.; Colored.; T. Pownall.
        Inset: A sketch of the upper parts of Canada.
      - A map of the middle British colonies in North America. First published by Mr. Lewis Evans, of Philadelphia, in 1755; and since corrected and improved, as also extended, with the addition of New England and bordering parts of Canada; from actual surveys now lying at the Board of Trade. By T. Pownall. London: J. Almon: 1776 [25 March 1776]., 757; Scale: 7 cm. = 90 mi.; Size: 49.3 x 82.4 cm.; Colored.; James Turner.; Lewis Evans and T. Pownall.
      - A new map of the western parts of Virginia, Pennsylvania, Maryland and North Carolina; comprehending the River Ohio, and all of the rivers, which fall into it; part of the River Mississippi, the whole of the Illinois River, Lake Erie; part of the Lakes Huron, Michigan &c. And all the country bordering on these lakes and rivers. By Thos. Hutchins. London: Hutchins: 1778 [1 November 1778]., 758; Scale: 1 in. = 20 mi.; Size: 90 x 110.3 cm.; Colored.; T. Cheevers.; Thomas Hutchins.
      - A map of the country between Albermarle Sound and Lake Erie, comprehending the whole of Virginia, Maryland, Delaware and Pennsylvania, with parts of several other of the United States of America. Engraved for the Notes on Virginia. The country on the eastern side of the Allegany Mountains, is taken from Fry and Jefferson's map of Virginia, and Scull's map of Pennsylvania, which were constructed chiefly on actual survey; that on the western side of the Alleganey, is taken from Hutchins, who went over the principal water courses, with a compass and log-line, correcting his work by observations of latitude; additions have been made, where they could be made on sure ground. [Paris: 1786]., 759; Size: 59.9 x 59.6 cm.; Colored.; Fry, Jefferson, Scull, and Hutchins.; S. J. Neele.
        The Society asked Thomas Jefferson in 1805 for a copy of his Notes on Virginia. Jefferson wrote 2 May 1805 and presented "a single copy remaining of the original edition printed at Paris, the only one almost perfectly correct, & was never sold, a few copies only having been printed and given to my friends" (Archives).
        In: Thomas Jefferson, Notes on Virginia.
      - [A map of part of Pennsylvania, Delaware and Maryland intended to shew, at one view, the several places proposed for opening a communication between the waters of the Delaware and Chesopeak Bays]. [1771]., 760; Scale: 2.5 cm. = 7¾ mi.; Size of plate: 31.2 x 44.6 cm.; J. Smither.; W. T. [Thomas] Fisher.
        The idea of a canal linking the Delaware River and Chesapeake Bay was of long standing when the Society formed a committee to arrange for a survey of the general area. Merchants of Philadelphia financed the early surveys and on 16 June 1769, Thomas Gilpin, one of the "Merchants' appointees," exhibited his plan of a canal with the elevation between Chester River and Duck Creek, and he included an estimate "for flat bottomed boats, carrying 1,000 bushels, £8050; for shallops &c., £28,298." The Society also received an elevation of the land between the Bohemia and Apoquinimy Rivers with the locks necessary to carry vessels from the tidewater of the Delaware to that of the Chesapeake. "The Distance from Tide to Tide is 5 Miles & 107 perches" (APS Minutes).
        W. T. Fisher (Thomas Fisher) delivered a map of the proposed canal 2 March 1770 which was
        intended to shew, at one View, the several places proposed for opening a communication between the waters of the Delaware and Chesapeake Bays... to be kept among the Society's papers for future use. In this Map is also delivered the different Roads proposed to be opened for Land Carriage
        from the Susquehanna River. On 2 November 1770, the "Abstract of Canal papers read & ordered to be printed. Fisher's map ordered to be engraved" (APS Minutes).
        The desire for this canal continued and it is interesting to note that as late as 16 December 1803 two of the maps belonging to the Society, the surveys by Anderson and Gilpin, were acknowledged as being in the possession of Benjamin Henry Latrobe. Latrobe had surveyed a route in 1799 and was named Engineer of the Chesapeake and Delaware Canal Company in 1804 when the first canal was dug.
        In: American Philosophical Society. Transactions, vol. 1.
      - [A map of part of Pennsylvania, Delaware and Maryland intended to shew, at one view, the several places proposed for opening a communication between the waters of the Delaware & Chesopeak Bays. 1789]., 760a; Scale: 2.5 cm. = 7¾ mi.; Size of plate: 31.2 x 44.6 cm.; J. Smither.
        In: American Philosophical Society. Transactions, vol. 1, 2nd ed. corrected (1789), opp. p. 367.
        Wheat: 305
      - A new map of the states of Pennsylvania, New Jersey, New York, Connecticut, Rhode Island, Massachusetts and New Hampshire, including Nova Scotia and Canada, from the latest authorities. New York: 1789., 761; Size: 27 x 40.3 cm.; C. Tiebout.
        In: William Gordon, History of the rise of the United States. New York: Hodge, Allen and Campbell: 1789. Frontispiece, vol. 2.
        Wheat: 150
        Presented by John Vaughan, May 1818; by the Estate of Richard Gimbel, 1974.
      - A chart of Delaware Bay and River, containing a full and exact description of the shores, creeks, harbours, soundings, shoals, sands and bearings of the most considerable land marks, &c. &c. Faithfully copied from that published at Philadelphia. By Joshua Fisher, together with the tide table from the capes to Philadelphia... London: Laurie and Whittle: 1794 [12 May 1794]., 762; Scale: 69½ English mi. = 1 degree.; Size: 46.8 x 68.6 cm.; Joshua Fisher.
        Original in North American pilot... London: Laurie and Whittle: 1800. No. 10.
      - A map of Pennsylvania, Delaware, New Jersey & Maryland, with the parts adjacent [1798]., 763; Scale: 2.5 cm. = 28 mi.; Size: 31 x 38.5 cm.; Thackara.
        In: Robert Proud, The history of Pennsylvania, vol. 2, frontispiece.
        Wheat: 312
        Presented by Robert Proud, 18 June 1802.
      - A map of the middle states, shewing the situation of the Genesee lands & their connection with the Atlantic coast. 1798., 764; Scale: [2.5 cm. = ca. 35 mi].; Size: 26 x 24.7 cm.
        In: Charles Williamson, Description of the Genessee country, following p. 37.
        Wheat: 313
      - A map of the middle states of North America, shewing the position of the Geneseo country comprehending the counties of Ontario & Steuben as laid off in townships of six miles square each. 1799., 765; Scale: 2.5 cm. = ca. 33 mi.; Size: 37.3 x 39.8 cm.; Maverick.
        In: Charles Williamson, Description of the settlement of the Genesee country, frontispiece.
        Wheat: 316
      - A map exhibiting the different stage routs, between the cities of New-York, Baltimore, and parts adjacent. To which is added, as an historical companion, the operations of the British army, from their landing at Elk River in 1777, to their embarkation at Nevisink in 1778. By John Hills. Philadelphia: E. Savage: 1800., 766; Scale: 2.5 cm. = 3 mi.; Size: 28 x 152.1 cm.; Colored.; John Hills.
      - [Map of Pennsylvania, Delaware and Maryland; showing proposed new roads and canals]. Plate VII, fig. 1. [Philadelphia: ca. 1800]., 767; Scale: 1 cm. = 3 mi.; Size of paper: 32.7 x 41 cm.; J. Smither.
        See: American Philosophical Society. Transactions, n.s., vol. 1, pl. 7: "An abstract of sundry papers and proposals for improving the inland navigation of Pennsylvania and Maryland, by opening a communication between the tide-waters of Delaware or Susquehanna, or Chesopeake Bay.. ." See Maps 760 and 760a, above.
      - A new map of the seat of war. N.p.: [ca. 1815]., 768; Scale: 1 in. = 42 mi.; Size: 34.2 x 46 cm.; J. Bower.; S. Lewis.
        Inset: Niagara River.
      - Map of reconnaissance between Baltimore and Philadelphia exhibiting the several routes of the mail-road contemplated by the resolution of Congress approved on the 4th of May 1826. U.S. War Department. [Washington: 1826]., 769; Scale: 1 in. = 3 mi.; Size: 22.3 x 79.6 cm.; S. Bernard and William Tell Poussin.
      - Map of the country between Washington & Pittsburgh referring to the contemplated Chesapeake & Ohio canal and its general route and profile. October 1826. Reduced from the general map, annexed to the report upon the contemplated canal, & drawn by Lieut. Farley... U.S. War Department. Georgetown, D.C.: 1826., 770; Scale: 1 in. = 8 mi.; Size: 45.4 x 64.5 cm.; Colored.; John Farley.; William Harrison and D. R. Harrison.
        Presented through Daniel Parker, 4 January 1833.
      - A map showing the effect of a connection between the Delaware Division and the Delaware and Raritan canal. Philadelphia: Watson's Lith.: [1835]., [ca. 1835].; 771; Size of paper: 49.2 x 65.8 cm.; Watson.
      - Geological map of the middle and western states. By James Hall. New York: Endicott Lithographer: [ca. 1848]., 772; Scale: 1 in. = 30 mi.; Size: 58.4 x 82.4 cm.; Endicott.; James Hall.
        Presented and autographed by Charles B. Trego.
      - General chart of the coast from Gay Head to Cape Henlopen. From a trigonometrical survey under the direction of F. R. Hassler and A. D. Bache. U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey. [Washington]: 1852., 773; Scale: 1:400,000.; Size: 78.3 x 95.3 cm.; F. R. Hassler and A. D. Bache.
        Contains six views and five sections of the slope of the ocean bottom.
      - Military maps illustrating the operations of the armies of the Potomac & James May 4th, 1864 to April 9th, 1865 including battlefields of the Wilderness, Spottsylvania, Northanna, Totopotomoy, Cold Harbor, the siege of Petersburg and Richmond. Battlefields of Five Forks, Jetersville & Sailor's Creek, Highbridge, Farmville & Appomatox Court-House. U.S. War Department. New York: J. Bien: 1867. 15 maps and title page., 774; Scale: 3 in. = 1 mi.; 1½ in. = 1 mi.; Size of paper: 61.1 x 45.4 cm.; Colored.; J. Bien.
        List of maps: 1. North Anna. 2. Cold Harbor. 3. Chancellorsville. 4. Harper's Ferry. 5. Fredericksburg. 6. High Bridge & Farmville. 7. Bermuda Hundred. 8. Jetersville & Sailors Creek. 9. Petersburg & Five Forks. 10. Totopotomoy. 11. Spottsylvania Court House. 12. The Wilderness. 13. Appomattox Court House. 14. Richmond. 15. Antietam.
        Presented by the U.S. War Department, 4 November 1870.
      - Map of the region between Gettysburg, Pa., and Appomattox Court House, Va., exhibiting the connection between the campaign and battle-field maps... under the direction of Brig. & Bvt. Maj. Gen. A. A. Humphreys... by N. Michler. U.S. War Department. [Washington]: 1869., 775; Scale: 1:300,000.; Size: 111.3 x 69.3 cm.; Colored.; N. Michler, John E. Weyss, C. Thompson, J. de la Camp, and A. A. Humphreys.
      - Map of the Buffalo, New York and Philadelphia R. R. and its principal connections. New York: [ca. 1880]., 776; Scale: 1 in. = 20 mi.; Size: 53.9 x 84.5 cm.; Colored.; F. S. Cook.
      - Post route map of the states of Pennsylvania, New Jersey, Delaware and Maryland and of the District of Columbia with adjacent parts of New York, Ohio, Virginia and West Virginia. Designed and constructed under the orders of the U.S. Post Office Department Postmaster General... by W. L. Nicholson. Washington: 1880. 1st ed. 1869., 777; Scale: 1 in. = 6 mi.; Size: 153 x 153 cm.; Colored.; C. H. Poole and W. L. Nicholson.; D. McClellan.
      - Map of the Buffalo, Pittsburgh & Western R. R. & connections. N.p.: 1881., 778; Size: 57.1 x 60.4 cm.; Colored.
      - Map of the railroads of Pennsylvania and New Jersey and parts of adjoining states. 1882. Prepared from official data by J. A. Anderson. Philadelphia: Smith and Stroup: 1882., 779; Scale: 1 in. = 8 mi.; Size: 98.5 x 121.5 cm.; Colored.; J. A. Anderson.
        Inset: Map showing the eastern shore of Maryland & Virginia.
      - Post route map of the state of New York, and parts of Vermont, Massachusetts, Connecticut, New Jersey and Pennsylvania. Also the adjacent portions of the Dominion of Canada, showing post offices, with the intermediate distances between them and mail routes in operation on 1st June 1884. [Washington]: 1884. 1st ed. issued 1868., 780; Scale: 1:380,160.; Size: 140.2 x 156.7 cm.; Colored.
        Insets: Postal service of Long Island, with the principal mail connections of the city of New York; map of the Lake St. Frances to Montreal area, Canada.
      - New York-New Jersey. New York sheet. U.S. Geological Survey. J. W. Powell, director. Surveyed in 1888-1889. [Washington]: 1888. Edition of 1892., 781; Scale: 1:62,500.; Size: 91.8 x 71.1 cm.; Colored.; Henry Gannett and J. W. Powell.
      - Bridgeport Quadrangle. New Jersey-Pennsylvania. Marcus Hook quadrangle. Pennsylvania-Delaware-New Jersey. U.S. Department of the Interior. Geological Survey. [Washington]: 1953. Edition of 1953., 782; 2 sheets.; Scale: 1:24,000.; Size: 57.7 x 44.6 cm.; Colored.
        Presented by George Washington Corner.
    - New York
      - A map of the countrey of the Five Nations belonging to the province of New York and of the lakes near which the nations of the Far Indians live with part of Canada taken from the map of the Louisiane done by Mr. Delisle in 1718. [1724]., 783; Scale: 2.5 cm. = 80 mi.; Size: 21.8 x 35.2 cm.; de l'lsle.
        In: Cadwallader Colden, Papers relating to an act of New York for encouragement of the Indian trade, frontispiece.
        Wheat: 317
      - A survey of Lake Champlain, including Lake George, Crown Point and St. John. Surveyed by order of... Jeffrey Amherst. By William Brassier. 1762. London: Robt. Sayer & Jn. Bennett: 1776 [5 August 1776]., 784; Scale: 2 cm. = 5 mi.; Size: 66.2 x 47.9 cm.; Colored.; William Brassier and Capt. Jackson.
        Inset: A particular plan of Lake George. Surveyed in 1756 by Capt. Jackson.
        This was removed from: The American military pocket atlas. R. Sayer and J. Bennett: [1776].
      - A map of the present seat of war on the borders of Canada. [Philadelphia: Aitken: 1775]., 785; Scale: 1 in. = 10 mi.; Size: 38.9 x 15.4 cm.
        At top of map is: "for the Penna Magazine p. 463" [see: Pennsylvania Magazine. 1775, vol. 1].
      - The southern part of the province of New York: with part of the adjoining colonies. By Tho[ma]s Kitchin, sen[io]r hydrographer to His Majesty. [London]: R. Baldwin: 1778., 786; Size: 24.7 x 18.4 cm.; T. Kitchin.
        At top of map is: "For the London Magazine 1778" [vol. 47, March 1778, p. 99].
      - From Albany (26) to Newborough. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 787; Size: 17 x 11.5 cm.
        Wheat: 349
      - From Albany (27) to Newborough. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 788; Size: 17 x 11.3 cm.
        Wheat: 350
      - From Albany (28) to Newborough. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 789; Size: 17 x 11.4 cm.
        Wheat: 351
      - From Albany (29) to Newborough. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 790; Size: 17 x 11.4 cm.
        Wheat: 352
      - From Albany (30) to Newborough. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 791; Size: 17 x 11.5 cm.
        Wheat: 353
      - From Albany (31) to Newborough. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 792; Size: 17 x 11.4 cm.
        Wheat: 354
      - From Albany (32) to Newborough. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 793; Size: 17x11.8 cm.
        Wheat: 355
      - From Albany (33) to Newborough. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 794; Size: 17 x 11.5 cm.
        Wheat: 356
      - From New York (1) to Stratford. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 795; Size: 17.3 x 11.4 cm.
        Wheat: 331
      - From New York (2) to Slratford [sic]. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 796; Size: 17.2 x 11.4 cm.
        Wheat: 332
      - From New York (3) to Stratford. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 797; Size: 17.2 x 11.4 cm.
        Wheat: 333
      - From New York (8) to Poughkeepsie. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 798; Size: 17.2x 11.5 cm.
        Wheat: 334
      - From New York (9) to Poughkeepsie. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 799; Size: 17.2 x 11.5 cm.
        Wheat: 335
      - From New York (10) to Poughkeepsie. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 800; Size: 17.2 x 11.4 cm.
        Wheat: 336
      - From New York (11) to Poughkee[p]sie. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 801; Size: 17.2 x 11.5 cm.
        Wheat: 337
      - From New York (12) to Poughkeepsie. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 802; Size: 16.7 x 11.3 cm.
        Wheat: 338
      - From New York (13) to Poughkeepsie. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 803; Size: 17.2 x 11.4 cm.
        Wheat: 339
      - From Poughkeepsie (14) to Albany. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 804; Size: 17.2 x 11.5 cm.
        Wheat: 340
      - From Poughkeepsie (21) to Albany. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 805; Size: 17 x 11.3 cm.
        Wheat: 344
      - From Poughkeepsie (22) to Albany. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 806; Size: 17.2 x 11.5 cm.
        Wheat: 345
      - From Poughkeepsie (23) to Albany. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 807; Size: 17.2 x 11.4 cm.
        Wheat: 346
      - From Poughkeepsie (24) to Albany. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 808; Size: 17.3 x 11.7 cm.
        Wheat: 347
      - From Poughkeepsie (25) to Albany. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 809; Size: 17.1 x 11.4 cm.
        Wheat: 348
      - From Stratford (18) to Poughkeepsie. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 810; Size: 17.1 x 11.3 cm.
        Wheat: 341
      - From Stratford (19) to Poughkeepsie. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 811; Size: 17.1 x 11.5 cm.
        Wheat: 342
      - From Stratford (20) to Poughkeepsie. [1789, 1961 reprint]., 812; Size: 17.1 x 11.5 cm.
        Wheat: 343
      - New York. Forts Erie, Schlosser, Niagara, Oswego and Schuyler are located. [1795]., 813; Scale: 2.5 cm. = 50 mi.; Size: 15.8 x 9.3 cm.
        In: Joseph Scott, The United States gazetteer, opposite "New-York." Incomplete.
        Wheat: 366
      - New York. [1796]., 814; Scale: 2.5 cm. = 60 mi.; Size: 14.6 x 19.3 cm.; W. Barker.
        In: Mathew Carey, Carey's American pocket atlas, following p. 46.
        Wheat: 367
      - Map of Ontario and Steuben counties [1798]., 815; Scale: 2.5 cm. = ca. 7 mi.; Size: 38 x 33.8 cm.; Fairman.; Heslop.
        In: Charles Williamson, Description of the settlement of the Genesee country, following p. 37.
        Wheat: 376
      - Map of Morris's purchase or West Geneseo in the state of New York. Exhibiting part of the Lakes Erie and Ontario, the straights of Niagara, Chautauque Lake and all the principal waters, the boundary lines of the several tracts of lands purchased by the Holland Land Company, William and John Willink and others. Boundary lines of townships: boundary lines of New York and Indian Reservations: laid down by actual survey; also a sketch of part of Upper Canada. By Joseph & B. Ellicott. 1800. N.p.: 1800., 816; Size: 51.6 x 66.6 cm.; and 52.2 x 66.8 cm.; Joseph & B. Ellicott.
        See: Ellis Paxson Oberholtzer, Robert Morris, patriot and financier. New York: Macmillan: 1903.
      - The state of New-York from the best authorities. 1800., 817; Scale: 2.5 cm. = ca. 38 American mi.; Size: 18.7 x 21.7 cm.; A. Anderson.
        In: John Payne, A new and complete system of universal geography, vol. 4, opposite p. 296.
      - A map of the state of New York. By Simeon De Witt. Albany: 1802 [16 October 1802]., 818; Scale: 69 mi. = 1 degree.; Size: 167.5 x 133.7 cm.; G. Fairman.; Simeon De Witt.
        Inset: Continuation of the state westward from the preemption line.
        Presented by Simeon De Witt, 5 January 1827.
      - Map of Morris's purchase or West Geneseo in the state of New York. Exhibiting part of the Lakes Erie and Ontario, the straights of Niagara, Chautauque Lake and all the principal waters, and boundary lines of the several tracts of lands purchased by the Holland Land Company, William and John Willink and others. Boundary lines of townships: boundary lines of New York and Indian Reservations: laid down by actual survey; also a sketch of part of Upper Canada. By Joseph & B. Ellicott. 1804. N.p.: 1804., 819; Scale: 1¼ in. = 6 mi.; Size: 52.2 x 67 cm.; Joseph and B. Ellicott.
      - A map of the state of New York. By Simeon De Witt. Contracted from his large map of the state 1804. New York: 1804 [19 March 1804]., 820; Scale: 69 mi. = 1 degree.; Size: 55.4 x 69.3 cm.; Colored.; Simeon De Witt.
        Mutilated: lower left corner is missing.
      - A map shewing the relative situation of a tract of land belonging to I. B. Church Esqr. New York: 1804., 821; Scale: 1¾ in. = 40 mi.; Size: 38.9 x 48.6 cm.; Jos. Fra[?].; Peter Maverick.
      - A map of the state of New York. Compiled from the latest authorities; including the turnpike roads now granted as also, the principal common roads connected therewith. By William McCalpin. Oxford: 1808., 822; Scale: 69 mi. = 1 degree.; Size: 41.6 x 51.2 cm.; William McCalpin.
        Presented by Robert Patterson.
      - Map of the northern part of the state of New York. Compiled from actual survey by Amos Lay. New York: 1812 [16 July 1812]., 823; Scale: 1:443,520.; Size: 76.2 x 126.2 cm.; Colored.; Amos Lay.
      - Plan of the siege of Plattsburg, and capture of the British fleet on Lake Champlain. The 11th Septr. 1814. [Philadelphia: ca. 1815]., 824; Size: 25 x 19.9 cm.; B. Tanner.
        This is to accompany Tanner's engraving of MacDonough's victory on Lake Champlain, copied from the painting by Hugh Reinagle.
        Presented by Henry Schenck Tanner, 20 February 1818.
      - Map of the north west part of the state of New York. Compiled from original surveys, by P. Tardieu. Paris: 1816., 825; Scale: 1 in. = 4½ mi.; Size: 59.6 x 72.9 cm.; Colored.; P. A. F. Tardieu and Richomme.; P. Tardieu.
      - Map of the Hudson between Sandy Hook and Sandy Hill with the post road between New York and Albany. New York: A. T. Goodrich and Co.: 1820., 826; Size: 252.6 x 22.8 cm.; Bridges.; Rollinson.
      - Map and profile of the Erie Canal; commenced 1817, finished 1825. N.p.: [ca. 1825]., 827; Scale: 1 in. = 6 mi.; Size: 22.7 x 116.2 cm.
        Presented by De Witt Clinton, 14 April 1826.
      - Survey for a ship canal around the Falls of Niagara. Made and drawn under the direction of Capt. W. G. Williams... by Lts. T. F. Drayton and J. G. Reed. U.S. Topographical Engineers. [Washington: 1835]., 828; Vertical scale: 50 ft. = 1 mi.; Size: 104.6 x 74.2 cm.; W. G. Williams, T. F. Drayton, and J. G. Reed.
        Insets: Engraving of Niagara Falls; Niagara River; U.S. north of the Ohio River and Upper Canada; Mouth of Four Mile creek with soundings adjacent.
        Presented through J. R. Ingersoll, 15 July 1836.
      - Survey for a ship canal to connect Lakes Erie, & Ontario. Lockport route. Profiles levelled and surveyed under the direction of Capt. W. G. Williams, U.S. Topographical Engineers, assisted by Lieuts. Drayton and Reed. [Washington: 1835]., 829; Size of paper: 60.6 x 137.2 cm.; W. G. Williams, T. F. Drayton, and J. G. Reed.
        See also map: 647: [1835]: Un38cfn Large.